再升高6英尺
Bring it up about six more feet.
好了 可以放下来了
Okay, you can go aheadabcand start dropping it.
下课
Class is over.
怎么回事 你是谁?
What's going on? Who are you?
我是医生
I'm a doctor.
你5年前是否做过角膜移植手术?
Did you have aabccorneal transplant five years ago?
是的
Yes.
其他接受了同一捐赠者器官的病人abc都已死亡或濒临死亡
Every other patient who had a transplantedabcorgan from that donor is either dead or dying.
带手提包了吗?
You got a purse?
我感觉挺好的
I feel fine.
我不是想吓唬你abc但其他人发病也很突然
I don't mean to scareabcyou,but so did the others.
一个活着 一个只剩半条人命
one living, one almost dead.
四个彻底死翘
Four fully dead.
没有任何共通点abc除了共同的捐赠者
Nothing in common except their donor.
Carl移植了新的心和肺
Carl got a new heart and lung.
但死因在肝脏
Liver kills him.
Tibalt得到了新的肝abc死因在肺
Tibalt got a new liver, lung killed him.
Holly得到了新的肾abc死于心脏病发
Holly got a new kidney,abcher heart blows up.
还有Frank 那个楼上呼吸困难的老头
And frank, the old guyabcgasping for breath upstairs,
当时接受的是肠移植abc现在胰脏却崩溃了
he got an intestinal graft,abchis pancreas is failing.
发病时间前后相隔不过8个月
All within eight months of each other.
而且均是突然出现严重并发症abc事前没有任何征兆
And in each case, serious complicationsabccame on suddenly and without warning.
指向心律失常abc大面积肺血栓 或脑出血
which means arrhythmia, massiveabcpulmonary embolus, or cerebral bleed.
Wilson为我做过什么?
What did Wilson do for me?
假设捐赠者受到感染 而没被检查出来
If the donor had an infection thatabcsomehow slipped by a screening,
病菌可能潜伏--
it couldabclay dormant--
5个器官系统分别受到攻击
five organ systems hit.
意味着有5种感染逃过了检查
Would need five infections forabcit to somehow slip by screening.
当然咯 他在雨天逗我笑abc让我看见从未注意的美丽颜色--
Oh, sure, he made me laugh on a rainyabcday, made me see the colors I never knew--
捐赠器官本身无一受到攻击
none of the donated organs were hit.
说明致病因子来自捐赠者的血液
It means whatever they gotabccame from the donor's blood.
这不能帮我们缩小--
That wouldn't helpabcus narrow down what--
可以推测谁不会发病
it narrows down who.
角膜移植不经血液abc这意味着Apple不会发病
Corneal transplants are bloodless.abcIt means apple's gonna be fine.
你能担保这个理论正确abc让她出院吗?
You secure enough in thatabctheory to send her home?
我想 可以先着手找Frank的病因
I guess we could wait till weabcfigure out what's wrong with frank.
但Gilbert Gottfried也能把我逗笑abc(喜剧演员)
On the other hand, gilbertabcgottfried makes me laugh.
世上到底有几种颜色?
And how many colors are there really?
只要你有红色 蓝色和绿色--
Once you got red,abcblue, and green--
他替你付午饭钱 喜欢怪兽卡车abc是你的良心...自身免疫性疾病
he paid for your lunch, liked monster trucks,abcand was your conscience. Autoimmune disease.
四名死亡病人的尸检中抗核抗体呈阴性
A.N.A. At autopsy of allabcfour victims were normal.
不能排除脉管炎 过敏性紫癜--
Wouldn't coverabcvasculitis.Henoch-schonlein purpura--
抗磷脂抗体水平也正常
antiphospholipid antibodies, normal.
那只剩下癌症了
Then that leaves cancer.
癌症有细分
Cancers have names.
需要演进过程
They have a progression.
只攻击特定的器官
They affect specific organs.
骨癌绝不会转化成肝癌
Bone cancer can'tabcturn into liver cancer.
不是癌症
Forget cancer.
是癌症
It's cancer.
不是癌症
It's not cancer.
你是对的 当然abc我在想什么呢?
You're right, of course.abcWhat was I thinking?
没有哪一种癌症会攻击3种器官
No single type of cancer blewabcup three organs in the chest
更别说压迫那个拳击手的脑干了
while also herniating inabcthe fighter's brain stem.
拳击手跟其他人没有联系
The fighter's irrelevant.
你向来不相信巧合
You don't like coincidences.
六个接受移植的病人都没有任何问题abc才是天大的巧合
It would be a coincidence if six transplantabcrecipients had nothing else wrong with them--
好比是个傻冒 让自己脑袋被打爆
like being an idiot, which leadsabcto getting your head knocked off.
而其他人患上了癌症
The others had cancer.
4次验尸和1000次实验室测试得出结论abc不是癌症
Four autopsies and about 1,000abclab tests say it's not cancer.
重做1000次测试和4次验尸
Redo the thousand testsabcand the four autopsies.
Taub和Kutner 查一下捐赠者
Taub and Kutner, check out the donor.
- 看哪种癌症--abc- 他并非死于癌症
- Find out which cancer--abc- he didn't die of cancer.
他在一次劳动事故中被削掉了脑袋
His head got chopped offabcin an industrial accident.
看哪种癌症原本可能导致他死亡
Find out which cancerabcwould have killed him.
去搜查他家和办公室abc有没有致癌物质 毒素--
Check the home and officeabcfor carcinogens, toxins--
他已经死了4年
he's been dead for four years.
他家大概早转租给别人了
I assume his home's beenabcrented to someone else by now.
看是哪种癌症杀死了他们
Find out which cancer killed them.
我把你忘了吗?
Did I forget you?
你可以去检查病人的眼睛
You can check out the patient's eye.
记在O'shea医生账上
Put this on dr. O'shea.
还有薯片
And some chips.
- 忘带钱包了吗 House?abc- 没
- Forget your wallet, house?abc- No.
把他的也算上
I'll take care of it.
搞定
Check.
你跟着我干嘛
Are you following me?
听说你喜欢怪兽汽车
Word is you're into monster trucks.
我孩子喜欢这个
My kids like it.
你不喜欢?
But not you?
"食肉兽"还行abc"加州路霸"纯属沽名钓誉
Predator's okay, but I think theabccalifornia crusher is overrated.
你对我有意思?
Are you checking me out?
你真醒目
You're astute.
不
No.
你那一把吃了多少药丸?
How many pills did you just take?
维可丁 鸦片类 还有维生素B12
Vicodin, opioids,some b12.
午后得提一下神
Need a little kick in the afternoon.
你不爽了吗?
You got a problem with that?
我想 我恋爱了
I think I'm falling in love.
她的眼睛不行了
her right eye's failing.
不 才没有
No, it's not.
其他人的移植器官都好好的
Everyone else's transplantedabcorgans were fine.
意味着她的眼睛也没问题
It means her eye is fine.
我们得摘除她的眼睛
We need to remove the eye.
这是她唯一能使的眼睛
It's her only working eye.
也可以摘除另一只 鉴于另一只不致命abc所以前一种做法正常一些
We could remove the other one,but since it's notabckilling her, I thought this way was less insane.
当你对我的所作所为感到不满
Do you have some ethicalabcproblem with what I'm doing
是否会以一种委婉的方式表达出来
that you could express in a uniqueabcway which might actually make me think
使我认识到自己错了abc尽管我永远不会承认?
that I'm wrong even thoughabcI'll never admit it?
会
Yes.
你真好玩
You are funny.
她的问题不在眼睛 而在脑袋里
The problem's not in herabceye. It's in her head.
你今晚想来我家看"激情处方"吗?
You wanna come over and watchabcprescription passion at my place tonight?
你知道我不是同性恋 对吧?
You know I'm not gay, right?
我也不是
Neither am I.
如果你不想做爱 也不打紧
If you don't want to haveabcsex,that's cool with me.
我不会去你家
I'm not coming over to your home.
我看上你了
I'll grow on you.
L...P...E...
L... P... E...
我非得和他住一间病房吗?
do I have to be in the same room as him?
不管他得了什么病 你也得了
Whatever he's got,you've got.
- 第5行abc- 你确定?
- Fifth line.abc- Are you sure?
十分确定 第5行
Pretty sure. Fifth line.
我要死了吗?
Am I gonna die?
能不能谈点除了你以外的话题?
Can we talk aboutabcsomething besides you for a moment?
譬如说 第5行?
Like maybe the fifth line?
F...E...O...S...P
F... E... O... S... P.
靠
Damn.
很抱歉abc我们必须摘除你的眼睛
I'm sorry. We need to remove your eye.
我的眼睛?
My eye?
不久前 你还以为你会死掉
A moment ago,you thought you were dying.
相比之下 失明要算好消息了
Blind's actually good news.
不幸的是 他错了
Unfortunately,he's wrong.
你刚做了视力检查
You just did the test.
她没有眯眼去看
She didn't squint.
意味着她的眼睛以为看到了
Which means the eye thinks it's fine.
- 你错了abc- 我知道 眼睛不会"以为"
- It was wrong.abc- I know. The eye doesn't think.
是脑子以为abc说明她脑子出毛病了
The brain thinks, which means if theabcthinking's wrong, the brain's wrong.
就是说已经扩散到了大脑abc现在摘除眼睛太晚了
Which means it's spread to the brain, whichabcmeans it's too late for us to remove the eye.
也就是说abc只能把她整个脑袋摘除
Which means we're gonna haveabcto remove your whole head.
别担心 一点也不痛
Don't worry. It doesn't hurt.
幻觉
Hallucination.
这是脑子的问题 对吧?
That's a brain thing, right?
引起幻觉的病因足有500种
500 different things canabccause hallucination.
不一定是神经上的
Doesn't mean it's neurological.
如果其他移植者的脑子都有毛病abc那就是它了
it does if one of the other organabcrecipients also had a brain issue.
他刚才手垂下了吗?
Did he just drop his hands?
没有 他们的脑子都没问题
No, none of them had brain issues.
如果看到他的瞳孔扩张 固定abc如果看到脸部抽搐...
if his pupils dilated, if his pupilsabcwere fixed,if there was a twitch...
他的脑袋受到重击abc然后挂了 没可疑
he got hit in the head,abche died,no mystery.
这正是你的观点
That was your point.
昨天的
Yesterday.
活到老 学到老
You live,you learn.
这是谁拍的?
Who shot this?
拳击馆的老板有台摄像机
guy who runs the gym has a camera.
把拍的恶心东西传到网上
Uploads the nasty stuff online.
看不到死者的正面
can't see the dead guy's face.
看不到他的脸 看不到抽搐abc看不到瞳孔--
I can't see his face,can't seeabcthe twitch, can't see the pupils--
我们知道网球手的心脏有问题
we know the tennis playerabchad a heart problem.
也许可以和吹号手的肺联系起来
We can maybe tie that toabcthe tuba player's lungs,
接着把这两者和地盘工人的肝联系起来
and then somehow tie both those things,abcto the construction worker's liver,
然后七拐八拐地绕到abcFrank崩溃的胰脏上面
and then possibly meander overabcto frank's pancreatic failure,
但没什么会同时引发脑子和心脏的问题
but nothing causesabcsimultaneous brain and heart problems.
癌症说不通
Cancer made no sense.
脑子和心脏的问题更说不通
The head and heart makeabcless than no sense.
这句话完全没意义
that makes no sense.
我知道 我只是强调这个观点
I know. I was making a point.
这就好 我还以为你是傻子
Oh, good. I thought you were an idiot.
你为什么要插话?
Why are you talking?
维修工不能发表意见吗?
Oh, the guy doing manualabclabor can't have an opinion?
搞不好我是个热衷于修理咖啡机的天才
I might be a genius who just happens toabchave a passion for fixing coffee machines.
不 显然我不是abc但对他人妄下论断很不礼貌
No, I'm obviously not,but that'sabcrude to make assumptions about people.
捐赠者的经历没有异常
Donor's history came up clean.
他在笑吗?
Did he just laugh?
不 不 我在打喷嚏
No, no, I sneezed.
他是个天才咖啡机修理工
he's a genius coffee repairman.
咖啡机修理工为什么会穿格子袜?
Coffee repairman who wears argyle socks?
我想我已经说过了abc不要对他人妄下论断
I thought I alreadyabctalked about not judging.
什么样的笨蛋会在工靴里穿格子袜?
What kind of idiot wears argyleabcsocks with construction boots?
我不是笨蛋
Uh, I'm not an idiot.
我只是--不善于伪装
I'm just--I'm notabcgood at disguises.
他是谁?
Who is he?
很明显 他是个很烂的私家侦探
He's apparently a veryabcbad private investigator.
那他为什么要假扮成咖啡机修理工?
Uh, why is he pretending toabcfix the coffee machine?
因为我想知道 在他发现什么之前abc你们这帮人能发现什么
Because I wanted to find out what you guysabcfound out before I find out what he found out.
我就可以知道abc是否需要雇一个私家侦探了
So I can find out if Iabcneed a private investigator.
还有呢?
So, nu?
没有任何异常感染abc死前12个月没有出国旅游
There's no history of unusual infections,abcno international travel in the 12 months--
说实话 我一向这么打喷嚏
No, seriously,that's how I sneeze.
他去了马德里和巴哈马
He was in madrid and the bahamas.
- 信用卡记录显示--abc- 女友付的钱
- Credit card receipts showedabcno-- - girlfriend paid.
他没有女友
There is no girlfriend.
她是他高中时的情人
She was his high school sweetheart.
他高中的情人嫁给了他最好的朋友
High school sweetheart isabcmarried to his best friend.
我知道
I know.
她4年前生了个小孩
She had a kid four years ago.
时间正好吻合
Timing fits.
她现在还是很正点
She's still pretty hot though.
你有任何与医学相关的发现吗?
You find out anything medical?
她的孩子有胃痛
The kid has a tummy ache.
还有 死者曾暴露在汞 金属模子
Also, the dead guy wasabcexposed to mercury, mold,
还有水合高氯酸环境下abc因为他们的爱巢正筑在...
and hydrous perchloric acid becauseabctheir sex pad was next to a garage
一间汽车修理厂隔壁abc后因发现有毒物质被铲倒清理
that was demolished afterabcthose toxins were found.
哦 对了 以上收费为2300元
Oh, yeah,that will be $2,300.
我给你开支票
I'll get you a check.
不 我不接受支票
No, I don't take checks.
你认为我会赖账?
You think I'm gonna stop payment?
- 你不会吗?abc- 当然会啦 2300美元太贵了
- Aren't you?abc- Of course, I am.
那价钱还包括abc那场拳赛从各个角度拍摄的影片
Actually, that price includes footage ofabcthe boxing match from four different angles.
30%的观众用信用卡买票入场
30% of the crowd paid by credit card.
我弄到了名单
I got their names.
其中四个带着摄像机 我把影片合到一起abc像航空航天局拍火星那般
Four of them had digital cameras, which Iabccomposited like nasa did for the pics of mars.
像漫游者探测器一样
You know, the rovers and all that.
瞳孔放大
pupils were dilated.
但手没有垂下来 说明还有肌肉紧张度
But he didn't drop his hands, whichabcmeans he maintained muscle tensity--
说吧
say it.
你是对的
You were right.
我还真是心胸狭窄
God, that was petty of me.
他是有肌肉紧张度abc但被打中时 暂时丧失
He maintained muscle tensity, but wasabcmomentarily distracted when he got hit.
那是颞叶癫痫
That's a temporal lobe seizure.
他请私家侦探是否就说明abc以后不用我们破别人家的门了?
Does that P.I. Guy mean we don't haveabcto break into people's homes anymore?
你们就是为了那个上医学院的
It's the whole reason youabcwent to medical school.
我可不想让你们没活干
I'm not gonna take that away from you.
- 他比我们好得多abc- 也贵得多
- He's better than we are.abc- And costs more.
活检脑部
Gonna biopsy the brain.
不
No.
说吧
Say it.
你是对的 但不行
You were right,but no.
颞叶控制着语言能力 听力和记忆
Temporal lobe controlsabcspeech, hearing, memory.
失去了这些功能 也许享受不到约会abc但至少--
She loses those things, she's gonnaabcbe a terrific date, but beyond that--
切掉她颞叶 很有可能她就成植物人了
we cut out a piece of it,goodabcchance she's a vegetable.
不用听不用说 更不用记
Nothing to hear,nothing toabcsay, nothing to look back on.
说得对啊 她的生命如此大好
You're right. She hasabcso muchto live for.
我们是否有个没几天可活的病人?
Do we have another patient who'sabcalmost finished with all their living?
因为他老就可以挖他脑子?
So it's okay to stab hisabcbrain because he's old?
不 因为要不挖他脑子 他就要死
No, it's okay to stab his brainabcbecause he's dead if you don'T.
让未来寡妇签同意书
Get the widow to say yes.
不行
no.
肺炎是胰腺衰竭的并发症abc这是可逆的
The lung inflammation is a complication ofabcthe pancreatic failure, which is reversible.
这是他最好的机会
This is actually his best chance.
如果我们能找出问题出在哪...
If we can find out what's wrong...
一个可能让他送命的测验怎么能...
how can a test thatabcwill probably kill him--
- 我不是说abc- 你说这风险极大的
- I didn't say-- - youabcsaid it was extremely risky.
那和让他送命有什么差别?
What does extremely mean?
求你了
Please.
抱歉 我做不到
I'm sorry. I can't.
我有丈夫
I have a husband.
有个两岁大的女儿 叫Julia
I have a two-year-old daughter.abcHer name is julia.
你能救她妈妈的命
You'd be saving her mother.
你撒谎
I think you're lying.
从没人来探望过你
You haven't had one visitor.
住院后没人打来过电话
Not one phone call sinceabcyou've been here.
她有孩子吗?
Does she have a child?
没有
No.
但她的生命依然值得...
But her life is still worth--
值得用我丈夫的命来换?
more than my husband's?
我撒谎是为了救自己的命 换你不会吗?
I lied to save my life. Wouldn't you?
不会想用别人的命来换
Not at another human being's expense.
不 你在抹杀我唯一的机会abc让你自己的丈夫再苟延残喘几天
No, you'd just rob me of my only chance so yourabchusband can struggle to breathe for a few more days.
闭嘴
Just shut up.
- 我不想听你说话abc- 女士们
- I don't want to hear from you.abc- Ladies.
- 你想恨我 这样就不会感到内疚abc- 闭嘴
- You want to hate me so you won't feel guilty.abc- Shut up!
Frank?
- 手术刀给我abc- Frank
- give me a scalpel.abc- Frank.
心脏停跳
He's coding.
准备
Clear.
- Frank!abc- 准备
- Frank!abc- clear.
准备
Clear.
- 签到同意书没?abc- 没有
- Did you get the consent?abc- No.
让foreman去弄
Tell foreman to get it.
老人家最怕黑人了
Old people are scared of black people.
没用了 病人已经死了
It won't matter. Patient's dead.
保存脑部
Save the brain.
尸检总不用同意书了吧
Don't need consent for an autopsy.
六分里能不能拿到一分 就看这下了
Well, at best, we're gonnaabcbat one for six on this one.
顶区和颞叶切片检查没什么
Thin slices through the parietalabcand temporal lobes were clean.
枕骨和前颞部分也没有发现--
Occipital and frontotemporalabcregions were also--
脑子没问题 继续
brain's clean.Moving on.
朝哪里继续?
To where?
我们完全没进展 现在还在倒退
We've gone from making no sense,to makingabcless sense, and then takena step backwards.
每个人都是某个器官遭到攻击而致命
Each of these people were killed byabcone thing that attacked one organ.
但都不是同一个器官
But never the same organ.
可能是捐赠者有两个毛病吗?
Could the donor haveabchad two things wrong?
或者六个毛病?
Or six things wrong?
新陈代谢疾病有专攻
Metabolic diseases specialize.
其他疾病也是 但癌症是通吃
Everything else specializes,abcbut cancer plays the field.
又回到癌症了?
You're back to cancer?
四处捣乱说得好听点就是癌症转移
Metastasis is just a fancyabcword for screws around.
哪种癌症?
Any type of cancer?
我不知道
I don't know.
癌症应该有迹象的
There would be evidence of cancer.
有的 但是我们还没发现
There is. We just haven't found it yet.
你就想是癌症abc那就有借口和Wilson说话了
You need it to be cancer so youabchave an excuse to talk to Wilson.
你给我个其他理由 能解释病人情况的
give me something else that explainsabcthis constellation of patients,
就让你叫我混球
then you can call mean ass.
我又没叫你混球
I didn't call you an ass.
肠穿孔
Perforated intestine.
如果原本是肠子里的正常细菌
If this thing started as normalabcbacteria living in the intestines
因肠壁上的血管异常进入血液
but got into a blood vessel throughabca vascular anomaly in the bowel wall,
就会通过血液循环影响到所有器官
then they would affect everyabcorgan through the blood stream.
搞砸一切
It screws up everything.
影响每一个人
For everyone.
好吧
Okay.
这虽然概率不大 我也可能是混球
It's a long shot,itabcis possible I'm an ass.
讽刺的是 要做个结肠镜来确认
Ironically, we need toabcdo a colonoscopy to confirm.
Apple进来的时候我们就里里外外检查了abc她没问题
we checked apple inside and outabcwhen she came in;she's clean.
异常应该是间歇性的abc要不他们一天内会死光
the anomaly would have to be intermittentabcor they all would have died within a day.
她才刚开始腹痛abc抓紧时机朝她屁股插根管子
she starts getting abdominal pain, shoveabca tube up her rear before it can get away.
再检测其他有腹痛症状的人
And test anyone else with stomach pain.
其他人都死了
Everyone else is dead.
非也
Not everyone.
捐赠者给了他们的东西之一就是基因
The one thing the donor gave toabceach of these people is his dna.
有没有别人携带了这基因的?
Anyone else have his dna?
你要给一个健康的四岁小孩abc做结肠镜?
you want to do a colonoscopyabcon a healthy four-year-old?
她肚子痛
She has a tummy ache.
如果被Kutner说中了 就不止是腹痛
If Kutner's right,it's not a tummy ache,
是致命的脑部 心脏 肺 肝或胰腺疼痛
it's a fatal brain or heartabcor lung or liver or pancreas ache.
我不会因为一种可能性极小的猜测
I'm not gonna scare theabchell out of the poor kid's mom
就把孩子的母亲吓个半死
because of a long shotabccorollary to a long shot theory.
那就跟她说实话吧
Fine. Tell her the truth.
问问爸爸知不知道abc亲爸爸是谁
Then ask if daddyabcknows who the real daddy is.
她一定要清醒吗?
does she have to be awake?
我们得让她告诉我们疼不疼
We need her to tell us when it hurts.
她会没事的
She'll get over it.
你丈夫可能承受不了
Your husband might not have.
如果小孩真的过来买冰激淋呢?
What if a kid wants ice cream?
标识上说 停止营业
The sign outside says 'closed.
O'shea医生不适合你
' Dr. O'shea's not right for you.
你发现什么了?
What'd you find out?
你调查他做什么?
Why are you investigating him?
我想知道他是不是借钱不要利息
'Cause I need to know if heabclends money interest-free.
你发现什么了?
What did you find out?
我要冰激淋
I want some ice cream.
学会识字再来吧
Not until you learn to read.
你本该信任朋友的
You're supposed to trust friends.
我不认识他 没有理由--
I don't know the guy.Iabcgot no logical reason--
和他做朋友?
to be his friend?
你看过放学后电视节目没?
Have you never seen anabcafter-school special?
友谊的乐趣之一:
That is part of theabcpleasure of friendship:
没有绝对的证据 就相信朋友abc且因为信任 得到了回报
Trusting without absolute evidenceabcand then being rewarded for that trust.
你在偷拍一个和自己妹妹发生婚外情的人
You're taking pictures of a guy who'sabchaving an affair with his own sister.
还敢和我说教信任的回报?
And you're lecturingabcme about the rewards of trust.
雇我的有两种人
There are two typesabcof people that hire me.
其实上是三种
No, actually,there are threeabctypes of people that hire me,
第三种人和我要阐述的论点无关
but the third type's irrelevant toabcthe point I want to make.
请你去这样烦人要收多少钱?
Do you have a special rateabcplan for being a pain in the ass?
一种是要证明他们是对的abc一种要证明他们是错的
One type wants to find out that they're right,abcone type wants to find out that they're wrong.
我是哪一种?
Which type am I?
你是第三种
You're the third type.
你先说和我无关的两种?
You lead with the irrelevant types?
你这种是不在乎自己是对是错
You're the type that doesn't careabcif you're right or wrong
因为你雇我查的人就是错的
because they've hired me toabcinvestigate the wrong person.
还真有这一种?
That's an actual type?
你想让我调查的是Wilson.
You want meto check out Wilson.
- 你想让我找出他是否--abc- 你怎么知道Wilson的?
- You want to find out if he's--abc- how do you know about Wilson?
看我是干那一行的?
What do I do for a living?
你调查过我?
Have you been checking me out?
这也要向我收费?
I've been paying for that?
到目前为止 你什么钱都没付
So far,you haven't paid for anything.
你想找出他是否痛苦
You want to find out he's pining;
你想找出是否有迹象说明他会回来
you want to find out if there's something aboutabchim that will tell you he's gonna come back
或能让你把他弄回来
or something you canabcuse to make him come back.
有吗?
Is there?
没 什么都没有
No, no, there's nothing.
抱歉
Sorry.
这些要900块
That will be $900.
我得走了
I gotta go.
我写支票给你
I'll get you a check.
结肠镜没有发现
Colonoscopy was clean.
那就剩癌症啦
Then that just leaves cancer.
孩子的结肠镜检查结果阴性abc什么也证明不了
The fact that the kid's colonoscopyabcwas negative doesn't prove anything.
什么也证明不了abc证明不了什么
Yes, the fact that it didn't proveabcanything didn't prove anything.
这观点好
Excellent point.
我们不知道孩子有没遗传什么
We don't know if theabckid inherited anything.
即使有 按照Kutner的理论abc这是间歇性的
Even if she did, Kutner's theoryabcis that the thing's intermittent.
穿孔发生在死前不久
The opening would have to beabcopen shortly before death.
不幸的是 只有在人死后abc才知道死前不久是哪个时点
Unfortunately, we can't know when shortlyabcbefore death is until shortly after death.
那可真是麻烦了
And that seems like an obstacle.
如果有别的办法呢?
What if there was a way around that?
那我们就算是白费功夫了
Then we're kind of allabcsweating over nothing.
不是对付死亡 而是绕过死亡
Not around death,aroundabcdeath as an obstacle.
我们要看看他的结肠怎么活动
We need to see his colon at work.
你知道死了就不活动了吧?
You do know what death means, right?
没有生命系统 就没有压力让体液流动
Without a living system, there's notabcenough pressure to get fluid all the way up.
生命是不能创造 但制造压力不难
Life we can't create,abcyet,but pressure's easy.
可以用通常测试心脏工作量的abc高压水喷射器
We use the same high pressure waterabcjet we use to test cardiac workload.
虽然他不会醒着告诉我们哪里痛
I mean, he's not gonna beabcawake to tell us where it hurts--
- 这不会abc- 就这样
- it's notabcgonna-- - do it.
好像堵住了
It's kinda stuck.
不是一般的堵
It's more than stuck.
肠子都死了六小时了
The bowel's been dead for six hours.
不管打什么进去都弄不开的
No matter what you shootabcup there, it's closed.
真是疯了
This is nuts.
这是可调整的哦
It's adjustable.
- 成功了abc- 是啊
- It's working.abc- Yeah.
还不够
Not much.
再加压
Increase the pressure.
内诊境弯曲了
The endoscope's bowing.
推到胃部
Push on the stomach.
这些只是正常体液
Those are normal bodily fluids.
是啊 正常的体内污水
Yeah, normal bodily sewage.
再加压力
Put the pressure back on.
到底了 没病变
That's the end. No leaks.
等等 那是什么?
Wait. What's that?
只是末端阴影
That's just dark'cause I'm at the end.
如果这还不是末端呢?
What if you're not at the end?
如果这是损伤呢?
What if it's a core lesion?
要不再加点压?
Maybe a little more pressure?
别加太多 要这真是末端了我就...
Not too much.
终于还是恶化了
it's finally accelerating.
Apple的心率变得不规律
Apple's heart rate has become irregular.
呼吸吃力
Breathing is labored.
结肠镜没查出病变
Colonoscopy's still showing no leaks.
会是自身免疫疾病吗?
What if it is autoimmune?
我们别再重复以前的对话行吗?
What if we don't have conversationsabcwe've already had?
5个中4个都活不了 病死了
Four out of the five didn'tabclinger. They got sick and died.
没时间去排除已经排除过的病
We don't have time to dismiss thingsabcwe've already dismissed.
没有一种病症说得通
Nothing fits.
这正是重复以前对话的一个例子
See, that's an example of aabcconversation we've already had.
她病了 肯定有病症说得通
She's sick. Something fits.
- 多发性硬化病?abc- 不是!
- Ms?abc- No!
从现在起 没有新建议就别发话
Okay, from now on,no one saysabcanything unless no one's said it before.
你去哪?
Where are you going?
给她脑脊液用免疫凝胶查隐藏蛋白指标
You guys start immuno-gels on her csfabcto look for hidden protein markers.
然后给她做基因测序
Then start sequencing her genes.
我要开始治疗了
I'm gonna start treatment.
- 按什么治?abc- 癌症
- Treatment for what?abc- Cancer.
不是癌症 化疗是很危险的
It's not cancer. Chemo's toxic.
反正是有病了
It's something.
那我们就得治病
Which means we shouldabctreat her for something.
她没事
She's fine.
她的表在哪?
Where's her chart?
你按紧急铃就是为了找她的表?
You rang emergency to get her chart?
我知道是我不好
I know. That was bad of me.
但是病人的表是应该扣在床尾
But I'm pretty sure the chart'sabcsupposed to be attached to the bed
这样病人快死时abc跛子医生就不用满医院找了
so that gimp doctors don't have toabclook all over the place while patients die.
非常感谢
Thank you so much.
有空的话给我来一杯胡椒薄荷茶
And some peppermintabctea when you get a chance.
我要你签点东西
I need you to sign something.
化疗同意书
Consent to chemotherapy.
你发现肿瘤了?
You found cancer?
没有
No.
- 那检测结果显示-- - 没有
- Then you have tests indicating--abc- nope.
那我为什么要签?
Then why should I sign it?
问得好
That's a good question.
值得我详细解答
It deserves a complicated answer.
安慰剂效应
Placebo effect.
人们对医生 诊断和药有信心
People have confidence in doctors, they haveabcconfidence in diagnoses, confidence in medicine.
有时候会因为心理作用而有点好转
Sometimes they get a little betterabcjust because they think they will.
这样会使我们误以为找对了路子
And that can make us think thatabcthe wrong answer is the right answer.
是很不好的
Which is very bad.
所以你有证据指明癌症但不能告诉我
So you do have proof that it'sabccancer but you can't tell me
因为这样会影响我对药物的反应?
because it might affect theabcway I react to the medicine?
要是真的如此 就会有影响
If that were true, and itabcwould certainly make sense,
你想我会告诉你这是真的?
do you think I couldabctell you that it's true?
眼角膜移植前我几乎什么都看不见
I was practicallyabcblind before the transplant.
2200度
2200 vision.
这些私事你不都跟Foreman医生谈过了?
Didn't you cover all this personalabcstuff with dr. Foreman?
你不在乎我以前是怎样的?
You don't care who I used to be?
你是个做过眼角膜移植手术的数学老师
You're a post-cornealabctransplant math teacher.
我猜你以前个是瞎数学老师吧
I deduced that youabcwere a blind math teacher.
我是个建筑师
I was an architect.
你看得到东西后 却不做建筑师了?
You gave up architecture afterabcyou could see?
世界太丑了
The world was ugly.
你觉得要是你没跛 世界会不同吗?
You think the world would be anyabcdifferent if your leg was fine?
不
No.
觉得要是你没跛 你会有所不同吗?
Think you'd be anyabcdifferent if your leg was fine?
医生说我能看见后 人生会更美妙
I mean, the doctors told me that my lifeabcwas gonna be so much better once I could see.
可以约会 可以跳舞
I would date, I would dance,
不过我以前讨厌共舞的人现在还是讨厌
but, uh, the guys I hated dancingabcwith before I hate dancing with after.
父母还是不在了
My parents were still dead.
我还是孤独一人
I was still alone.
你很有趣
You're fun.
你还不跟我一样
You don't seem all that different.
我还没放弃
I haven't given up.
Wilson找到新工作 没开始上班 但是--
Wilson's got a newabcjob,hasn't started yet, but--
我们要跟踪谁?
so who are we following?
看到那个女人吗?
See that lady up there?
你直接指着目标?
you point at the target?
不 我跟着的人在这点和这点之间
No, I'm following the one halfwayabcin between that point and that point.
美人
Pretty.
- 谁请你查她的?abc- 没人 我只是喜欢她
- Who hired you?abc- No one. I just like her.
你在盯她的梢?
You're stalking her?
不 我从那书店开始跟着她的
No, no, I followed her out ofabcthat bookstore back there.
你是在盯她的梢 只是时间不很长
You are stalking her,justabcnot for very long.
你还有什么我会关心的事要说说?
So what else can you tellabcme that I might care about?
他参加了一周两次的哀伤咨询
He attends this griefabccounseling thing twice a week
他们聚集在那为亲人的故去大哭
where they go around the roomabcand cry about who's dead.
Cameron去过几次他家
Cameron's been to his house several tis,
他们只是聊失去爱人的感觉
they just talk about deathabcand losing loved ones.
什么 你在干什么--
What-- whatabcare you--
要是她转过头 就会发现我们走回头路了
if she turns her head, she's gonna seeabcthat we're walking the wrong direction.
不 她不会的 我不容易让人留下印象
No, no, no,she won't.abcI'm very nondescript.
但我不是啊
Well, I'm not.
那你走在我身后四步开外吧
Well, then you stay four feet behind me.
你怎么知道他们聊些什么?
How do you know whatabcthey're talking about?
我也参加了同一个咨询组
I'm in the same grief counseling group.
最近母亲过世了
I recently lost my mother.
要是你说死了孩子更容易泡到妞
You'd get laid more often ifabcyou told them you lost a kid.
我孩子没死啊
I didn't lose a kid.
你是个不会说谎的私人侦探?
You're a P.I. Who can't lie?
我会说谎 只是不太擅长
I can lie. I'm justabcnot all that good at it.
Cuddy医生去过2次Wilson家abc并打过几次电话给他
Well, dr. Cuddy's been overto Wilson'sabctwice and phoneda bunch of times.
Foreman打过几次电话
Foreman called him.
其他时间 Wilson读冥想书籍abc和修建库房的杂志
And the rest of the time Wilson's been readingabcmeditation books and magazines about restoring barns.
- 你们在跟踪我abc- 没有
- Are you following me?abc- no.
你们说谎?
Are you lying?
- 没有abc- 是的
- No.abc- Yes.
撒谎技术第一课: 投入
Lesson one:Commit.
让我很不安
It's making me uncomfortable.
对不起
Sorry.
你很漂亮
You're very pretty.
更不安了
More uncomfortable.
她不适合你
She's not your type.
你适合蠢一点的
Your type is much stupider than her.
Wilson有说起我吗?
What did Wilson say about me?
从没提起过你
Oh, you've never come up.
在哀伤咨询中 还是其他场合
In the grief counseling orabcin the other--
都没有 我在他家装了3个窃听器abc他车里也装了一个
anywhere,I got three bugs inabchis home and one in his car.
如果我不是先认识你abc根本察觉不出有你存在
If I didn't know you, Iabcwouldn't even know you existed.
这算好消息
Which is good news.
你会忽视两样东西
Only two things you ignore--
不重要的 和你希望它不重要的
things that aren't important andabcthings you wish weren't important.
可希望常常落空
And wishing never works.
她好多了
She's better.
我一眼就看出来了
I can tell at once.
呕吐是化疗的副作用
Vomiting's a side effect of the chemo.
心率稳定 呼吸顺畅了
Her heart rate'sabcstabilized, breathing's good.
淀粉酶和甘油三酸酯指标降下来了
Amylase and triglycerides areabcboth coming down.
我想起作用了
I guess it's working.
真不敢相信
Can't believe it.
是癌症
It's cancer.
不是癌症
It's not cancer.
检测表明病人好一些了
Labs show that our patient is healthier.
还会恶化
She's gonna get sicker.
会死
Then she's gonna die.
我买了泰国菜
I brought thai food.
- 你发现了什么?abc- 没发现
- What did you see in her?abc- Nothing.
不是癌症
It's not cancer.
检测表明不是癌症
All the tests say it's not cancer.
检测数据一开始就表明不是癌症
They've always said it's not cancer.
治疗有效果证明了是癌症
Treatment proves it's cancer.
治疗效果证明可能是
Eh, treatment proves it could be cancer.
但这不是癌症
It's not cancer.
这可是你自己的诊断
This was your diagnosis.
我从不认为是癌症
I never thought it was cancer.
你使用了针对癌症的治疗
You treated for cancer.
我认为她的病有着癌症的表相
I thought that what sheabchad acted like cancer.
如果表现得像癌症abc也许对治疗的反应也会像癌症
If it acts like cancer,maybeabcit'll respond like cancer.
确实反应像 因为就是癌症
It did. 'Cause it's cancer.
得揪出这个走着唱着都像癌症
We have to find something that walksabclike cancer, talks like cancer,
却不是癌症的家伙
tastes like cancer,but isn't cancer.
我们不干
No, we don't.
好转了就行了 管它什么原因呢
Better is better. Who cares why?
我在乎 Tetrault也在乎
I do. And so does tetrault.
谁?
Who?
那个死了的吹号手
The dead tuba player.
Tibalt
Tibalt.
关键在于他最后一个死 还是死了
The point is,he died last, but he died.
说明她也会死
Which means she's gonna die too.
Tibalt 没有服用治疗癌症的药物
Tibalt wasn'tabcreceiving cancer medication.
有一种治癌药私下被用来治疗关节炎
there's a cancer drug that'sabcused off-label for arthritis.
他没得关节炎
There's no record of arthritis.
有没有询问过所有学吹大号的学生?
Did you interview all the tuba students?
如果他手上关节痛 不可能弹奏
If he had joint pain in hisabchands, he couldn't have played.
那就不是手关节
Then it wasn't in his hands.
为什么要关注他的学生?
Then why do we care about his students?
其中有个学生是加拿大人
One of them is canadian.
帮他带甲氨蝶呤 来掩盖关节炎
Brought him methotrexate soabche could hide his arthritis.
他已经负担不起高昂的医疗保险了
Already couldn't afford his insurance.
这一小段花了我700块才查到
And that little pieceabcof business cost me $700.
我打算把这价格再抬高 转嫁在病人的身上
I'm gonna pass it on toabcthe patient with a steep mark-up.
说不通
This makes no sense.
我知道
I know.
想要她不死 就得找出什么酷似癌症
She's dead unless weabccan find what's cancer...
却不是癌症
but not cancer.
漏掉了什么
Something's missing.
我需要启示
I need an epiphany.
你开价多少?
What are you billing out at?
300块一个小时?
$300 an hour?
这里是400
Here's four.
有别的肿瘤学家
There are other oncologists.
有更棒的 但我需要你
Better oncologists. But I need you.
我来描述病症和困惑 你想到什么说什么
Let me describe the symptoms, problems,abcissues, and say whatever you feel like saying,
直到我脑子里灵光闪现
until somethingabctriggers an idea in my head.
不要胡来了
That's not the way it works.
你想问题有自己一套
You have a way of thinking about things.
松散随意 曲里拐弯
It's sloppy,it's undisciplined,abcit's not very linear.
恰能补足我的思维
It complements mine.
能带我驶向意想不到的路途
It drives me down avenues thatabcI wouldn't otherwise--
House 走吧
house, please go away.
似癌症 却不是癌症
Cancer, but not cancer.
对癌症的治疗手段有反应 但--
Responds to cancerabctreatment,but there's no--
你好吗?
how are you?
请你别这样
Don't do this. Please. Please.
别这么任性
Don't do this.
我要向前看
I'm trying to move on.
和Cameron来往 和Cuddy Foreman通电话abc却不理我
By hanging out with cameron, talkingabcto cuddy,foreman, but not me.
我雇了私家侦探监视你
I paid a privateabcinvestigator to spy on you.
太过分了
You didn't.
你想离开我abc就得面对我 和我讲清楚
You want to move on from me, youabcgot to deal with me,talk to me.
你没权利--
You had no right--
我们不是朋友了
we're not friends anymore.
没有信任 就谈不上违背
There's no trust to be breached.
我可以找人跟踪你 可以骂你abc到处八卦你的秘密
I can have you followed, I canabccall you names,tell your secrets.
Foreman做了CT
Foreman did a ct.
颞区和额顶骨区正常
Temporal andabcfrontoparietal regions are normal.
枕叶正常
Occipital lobe, normal.
我不想再见到你 House
I have the right to walkabcaway from you, house.
我想开始没有你的生活
There's a world beyond you.
你得明白 就算你不愿意abc我已经开始新的生活了
You need to realize that,andabceven if you don't, I'm moving on.
下次你来敲门 我不会开的
The next time youabcknock, I'm not answering.
还没灵感 继续说
Nothing yet. Keep talking.
真遗憾
I'm sorry.
你偷听我谈话 还收费?
You charge me for listeningabcin on my own conversations?
是啊 何乐而不为?
Yeah, why wouldn't I?
-你有多少朋友?abc-17个
How many friends do you have?
真的假的? 你列了名单?
Seriously? You have a list?
不 我知道其实你是想谈你自己
No, I knew this conversation wasabcreally about you,
所以 我给你个答案abc你就可以沿着自己的思路继续了
so I just gave you an answer so youabccould get back to your train of thought.
聪明abc我只有一个朋友 现在也没了
Well done. I have one. Had one.
朋友很重要
You know,friends are important.
- 你会错过--abc- 闭嘴
- You're gonnaabcmiss-- - shut up.
朋友不过是省得你一个人在房间里枯坐
Friends allow you to notabcsit in a room by yourself.
这谈话你收费吗?
Are you charging me for this?
- 我们是朋友吗?abc- 不是
- Are we friends?abc- No.
那就收
Then yes.
- 你想当我朋友吗?abc- 不 你有点吓人
- Do you wanna be my friend?abc- No. You scare me a little.
他觉得如果他不是我朋友 就不能跟我说话
He thinks if he's not aabcfriend,he can't talk to me.
我们当然可以说 就像两个正常人说说话--
We can talk, we can be twoabchuman beings talking--
对不起 我支持他abc不好意思打断你了
I'm with him.Sorry.abcDidn't mean to interrupt.
你是打断了
Yes, you did.
我话刚说了一半
I was in the middle of a sentence.
我是打断了abc可你一直在用这种思路考虑问题
Yes, I did. You're repeating yourself.
谢谢 证明一下
I'm grateful. Make your point.
就像你之前说的'是癌症 但又不是癌症'
It's like that"cancer, but not cancer"abcthing you were talking about before.
朋友是朋友 客户是客户abc一就是一 二就是二
Friends are friends, customers are customers,abcand everything elseis everything else.
如果不这样 那就都乱套了
If it's not,nothing's nothing.
或者说万事皆有可能
And anything can be anything.
- 10点10分 停止收费abc- 什么?
- 10:10. Stop the clock.abc- What?
世界没有她想得那么丑陋
The world is not asabcugly as she thinks it is.
是癌症 但又不是
Cancer, but not cancer.
这说不通 除非...
Doesn't make any sense unless...
病人大脑也不是大脑
brain, but not brain.
枕叶正常 可她眼睛失明
Occipital lobe's normal.abcBut her eyes suck.
枕叶应该起到代偿视力的作用
That lobe should be compensating.
既然没有 那就说明大脑里有不该有的东西
Since it's not, that tells me that something'sabcin there that shouldn't be in there.
是大脑 可又不是
Brain, but not brain.
你为什么来我的办公室?
Why are you in my office?
要找出病变 我得切下她的头顶盖
To find the anomaly, I needabcto chop off the top of her head.
没你批准就做不到
Pretty sure I need yourabcapproval for that.
我打算相信你的第一直觉
I'm gonna trust your first instinct.
你这么说把我弄糊涂了
I'm not usually confused whenabcyou say things like that.
我让他们继续按癌症给她治疗
I'm ordering herabccancer treatment to be continued.
怎么修个咖啡机花了2300块?
Why does it cost $2,300 toabcfix a coffee machine?
是存在肿瘤干细胞
Cancer stem cells are real.
它们是一切问题的答案
They explain everything.
它们就像胚胎干细胞
They're like embryonic stem cells.
想变成什么就变成什么
They become whatever they want.
捐赠人是携带者 所以感染了器官接受者
Donor had them, the recipients got them.
这些细胞随着血液流动 停到某个器官上
They floated around,theyabclanded on an organ,
浸润在细胞群中 部分分化
got bathed in cytomes andabcpartially differentiated.
关键就在于'部分'
And the key word there is partially.
在大号手体内 它们变成肺abc但又不是肺
In the tuba player,theyabcbecame lung, but not lung.
在网球选手体内 它们变成心脏abc但又不是心脏
In the tennis player,abcthey became heart, but not heart.
如果你明白规律了 就让我闭嘴
Stop me if you'veabcfigured out the pattern.
看起来是器官的一部分abc可并没有发挥器官的功能
They looked as if they belonged,abcbut they weren't doing their jobs.
当需要这些器官发挥作用的时候abc就出事了
And when they were really needed, boom.
化疗起作用是因为abc这些细胞基本算是肿瘤
Chemo worked becauseabccells are basically tumors.
化疗抑制了它们
Chemo shrunk them.
你还是不同意 对吧?
You're still gonna say no,aren't you?
你没法证实
You've no proof.
我有大脑扫描结果
I have the brain scan.
结果是正常的
The normal brain scan.
所以我才需要切下她的头顶盖
This is whyI need to take off her head.
为了治疗 还是为了证明你是对的?
To treat or to prove you're right?
为了治疗
To treat.
化疗什么也治不好
Chemo's not killing anything.
只会隐藏真正的问题
It's just hiding the real problem.
她会病危的
She's gonna crash.
等到她病危时候 那就太迟了
If we wait until she doesabccrash, it might be too late.
那下一步是什么?
So the next step is what?
我不同意 你就想办法让她病危abc然后我会相信你的理论是正确的?
I say no, and then you do something to make herabccrash so that I'll think you've proven your theory?
我绝不会这么做
I would never do that.
是的 你做不到
No, you won't.
* 改变世界 *
* To change the world *
* 迈出第一步 *
* start with one step *
* 无论步伐多微小 *
* however small *
* 第一步永远最艰难 *
* the first stepis hardest of all *
* 一旦步上正轨 *
* once you get your gait *
* 你便可昂首向前 *
* you'll be walking tall *
* 你说你从不尝试 *
* you said you never did *
* '因为害怕失败' *
* 'cause you might die tryin' *
* '因为你 *
* 'cause you if you *
* 如果闭上眼 *
* close your eyes *
* 房子失火*
* because the house is on fire *
* 你觉得无法动弹 *
* and think you couldn't move *
* 直到大火熄灭*
* until the fire dies *
病人病危！
She's crashing! *
* * '因为害怕失败' *
* * 'Cause you might die tryin' *
* '因为害怕失败' *
* 'cause you mightdie tryin' *
你该检查一下她的静脉注射
you might want to check her iv.
从我这看起来 吊瓶里装的像是盐水而不是化疗液
From here, it looks likeabcsaline instead of chemo.
它们是一模一样的
Yeah, they look identical.
是的
Still.
你也许还是该检查一下
You should probably check.
你把她的药掉包了?
You switched her meds?
怎么可能? 我都没法接近她
How could I? I had no access.
进行缝合
Close her back up.
继续手术
Do the surgery.
- 没理由做--abc- 没理由不做
- There's no reasonabcto-- - no reason not to.
麻烦危险的部分已经完成了
The stupidly dangerousabcpart is already over with.
可以置入神经感应网
We're ready with the neural net.
那是人脑吗?
Is that someone's brain?
部分是 部分不是
Except for the part that isn't brain.
嘿 这个病人是我--
Hey, that'sabcthe patient I--
你说她会没事的
you said she'd be fine.
我比你会撒谎
I'm a better liar than you are.
我掉包了她的药
I swapped her meds.
她大脑有问题abc我可能会害死她的
I mean, she's got a brainabcproblem. I coulda killed her.
是的
Yup.
感应网会显示出她的神经元反应速度
The neural net will show usabchow fast her neurons are firing.
如果有什么东西挡道了 比如说...
If there's something in the way, say...
不是大脑的那一部分abc正常的神经脉冲
brain that's not brain,abcthe normal neural impulses
会被吸进漩涡中 不能正常运作
will be sucked into a vortex becauseabcthey're not able to do their job.
然后由计算机处理 给出图片abc告诉我们该切除哪部分
The computer will then process itabcand give us a picture of where to cut.
酷
Cool.
什么?
Excuse me?
抱歉 我以为这是你想要的回答
Sorry, I thought that'sabcwhat you wanted to hear.
你觉得这一切都酷得不可思议
You think all this is amazingly cool.
你没有朋友abc所以你花钱雇我当听众
And you have no one else,abcsoyou're paying a guy to listen.
抱歉--不过是想帮你省点钱
Sorry--just tryingabcto save you some cash.
你在计时?
I'm on the clock.
当然了 为什么不呢?abc你以为我对这感兴趣?
Yeah, why wouldn't you be? Youabcthink this is interesting to me?
House?
house?
我找到了
I see it.
- 你能切下来吗?abc- 可以
- Can you get it?abc- I think so.
看来你没害死她
Turns out you didn't kill her.
酷
Cool.
你差我5000块
You owe me $5,000.
为什么你楞在那 House医生?
Why are you justabcstanding there,dr. House?
你怎么知道我是谁?
How'd you know who it is?
我闻出来的
I can smell you.
是啊 就像一片玫瑰花似的
Yeah, like you're a field of roses.
薄荷茶
Peppermint tea.
你知道'狼来了'的故事吗?
You ever hear of the boy who cried wolf?
从不相信
Never really bought that.
不管小孩喊多少次 他要被狼吃了abc妈妈就会跑来了
I don't care how often a kid cries, he's beingabceaten by a wolf,mom's gonna come running.
世界很丑陋
The world is ugly.
人们互相残杀
People kill.
永不满足
They go hungry.
仅仅为了证明我的观点
Just proving a point.
人们都像混球
People are asses.
为什么跟我说这些?
Why are you telling me this stuff?
因为世界不像你想得那么丑陋
Because the world is notabcas ugly as you think it is.
移植的角膜正常 眼睛也正常abc可你的大脑没有正常运作
Your transplanted cornea's fine,your eyeabcis fine, but your brain wasn't working right.
现在我把纱布揭下来
I'm gonna take theabcgauze off your eyes now.
- 会很亮abc- 我知道
- It's gonna be bright.abc- I know.
非大脑细胞部分导致不能正确处理视觉信息
The brain cells that weren't brain cells were inabcthe way of processing visual information correctly.
移植后 你能看见 但不是真正看见
After the transplant,youabccould see, but not see.
我能看见 我能读书
I could see. I could read.
是 但你看到的暗沉 雾蒙蒙abc或者是灰色的 我不确定
Yeah, but it was dull,orabcfoggy, or gray. I don't know.
我能确定是你看到的abc和其他人看到的不一样
What I do know is that you were notabcseeing what everyone else was seeing.
那现在呢?我看到的会...
And now? Things are gonna be...
很美吗?
beautiful?
你会看到事物的原貌
Things'll be what they are.
我看起来怎样?
How do I look?
很伤心
You look sad.
有没有法子让你来当我的助手?
Is there any way I couldabcput you on retainer?